<book>
    <type>book1</type>
    <lang>NALHAIM</lang>
    <pages>
        <page>IMG_shab_genealogical_tree</page>
        <page>A Brief History of the Cattgar Empire. Part I
            Lucius Magrod, Nullheim historian.

            The first mention of Cattgar as a single country dates back to the beginning of the 4th century BC.
            The disparate tribes united under Sultan Khamag-Shaba, the first known ruler of these lands.
            Before his arrival, there were five large separate tribes and countless smaller associations in the territory of Cattgar.
            Khamag-Shab was born into the Gushman tribe, the largest of the tribes that lived on the Cattgar Plain.
            Of course, the Sultan seized power over his neighbors by force, killing all his rivals.</page>
        <page>After making many powerful enemies, Hamag-Shab lived only three years after the formation of the Cattgar Empire, when he was killed in his palace by a sent assassin.
            But the dynasty he founded was able to resist, which is the merit of the two eldest children of Hamag-Shab, Amar-Shab, who became the second sultan of Cattgar, and Rivonna-Shab, his younger sister, who took the post of commander of the united army of the empire.
            In order to avenge her father's death and strengthen her brother's power, Rivonna launched a mass repression, ravaging the capitals of the four subordinate changes, because of which she entered the history of Cattgar as Rivonna the Cruel.
        </page>
        <page>Amar Shab was not famous for anything other than his term of office, sitting on the throne for twenty-four years and dying of illness in his bed. After the death of Amar-Shab, he left three sons, Umir-Shab, Voga-Shab and Dekat-Shab. Umir was the eldest of the brothers, and was supposed to take the throne of his father, but immediately after receiving the news of the death of his brother, Rivonna deployed her troops and led them to the capital.
            Capturing the palace almost without resistance, she found all her nephews and executed them by placing their heads on pikes in front of the palace entrance.
            Rivonna turned out to be not a wealthy ruler, in the three months that she ruled Cattgar, she managed to set against herself the elites of all five tribes and the broad masses of the population.
        </page>
        <page>She was arrested and publicly executed by her guards, after which the miraculously surviving Decath-Shab, the youngest of Amar-Shab's children, was introduced to the people. The rule of Decat-Shaba was marked by a long period of peace and the development of state institutions. He created the judiciary, the Sultan's Council, and wrote the "Treatise on the rights and duties of the inhabitants of the empire," the first document to legislate the rights of ordinary people who lived in Cattgar.
            Historians still debate whether Decath-Shab was an impostor, or whether he actually escaped death at the hands of his aunt.
            During the reign of Decates, the first mention of the Rashan Caliphate was recorded, which was already increasing its subjectivity.
        </page>
        <page>At that time, the main threat to Cattgar (apart from internal divisions) was the southern tribes of Yorg-Sabbar, who periodically raided the outskirts of the empire and devastated small settlements.
            Decates entered the history of his country as a progressor and died at the age of 49 from overeating.
            The throne passed to Ramul-Shab, the eldest son of Decat-Shab. Ramul was the first ruler to face the Mold. Without paying due attention to this environmental problem, Ramul allowed the loss of a significant territory in the south-west of the empire.
        </page>
        <page>This led to riots in the areas bordering the Mold, and the empire had to send troops to contain the influx of refugees and the spread of spores inland. Ramul was the first sultan to pass the throne to his heir during his lifetime.
            His son Tsurra-Shab took over the reins of government from his father when the health of the old sultan deteriorated so much that he could no longer fulfill his duties. Zurra was a very cruel ruler, famous for his love of personally executing criminals sentenced to death, most of whom were accused of attempting the life of the Sultan.
            Towards the end of his life, Zurra lost his mind, falling into paranoia.
        </page>
        <page>He saw traitors and enemies everywhere, had every window in the palace walled up, and spent the rest of his days in total darkness. His lifeless body, tightly clutching the blade of Rivonna the Cruel, was found by the councilors in the depths of the palace.
            Tsurra did not leave a direct heir, and until his niece, Agma-Shab, grew up, the Regen Council ruled the empire.
            The council members quickly began a power struggle, planning to marry little Zurra to their sons. Eight attempts were made on the life of the princess, but they all failed thanks to her faithful bodyguard from Nallheim, Claudus Cymer.
        </page>
    </pages>
</book>